<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rich with Agility</title>
    <link>http://richvisotcky.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rich with Agility</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 16:35:13 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://richvisotcky.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility and the Healthy Organization</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 16:35:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A coworker recently pointed me to an image from a SolutionsIQ blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.solutionsiq.com/the-third-wave-of-agile/&#34;&gt;The Third Wave of Agile&lt;/a&gt; which I’ve included below.  The article does a great job of describing these developments in Agile thinking, the organization around them by a group of people, historical markers of materials and events that affect the wave, and the divergence and convergence of ideas on how to solve the problem the wave represents.  It’s a good read, one to add to your list &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; this post. &amp;lt;wink wink&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/waves-of-agility.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/waves-of-agility.png&#34; alt=&#34;© 2016 SolutionsIQ. All rights reserved.&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        © 2016 SolutionsIQ. All rights reserved.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The article makes many references back to software development, and rightly so given the history of where these practices originated and are currently applied, yet brings light to the fact that the ideas in each wave are beginning their entry into other domains, and as we move into Business Agility this becomes even more prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got something a little different out of the graph, ideas around what people are asking for versus what they feel or fear they need even if they aren’t ready to admit it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each wave is basically a problem statement.  It’s saying &amp;ldquo;How do I/We do &amp;lt;insert wave&amp;gt; well?&amp;rdquo;  The higher the crest, the more pundits you see crawling out from cracks in the walls, descending from the skies, arriving by the boatload to state their opinion.  All of them, every single one, are &lt;strong&gt;LOUD&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/vikings.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/vikings.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problems people are really bringing forward are rarely phrased that way.  Instead I more often hear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want to build this awesome product.  How can I get my team to do it without taking 18 months?&amp;rdquo; - &lt;em&gt;Agile Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want to build this awesome product and have money to throw out the window, so I hired 70 people out of the gate so I can get this done in 4 months.  How can I get them to build the product without taking 3 years?&amp;rdquo; - &lt;em&gt;Agile Teams, Agile at Scale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have all these great teams, and my product is a mess.  How do I get it back on track?&amp;rdquo; - &lt;em&gt;Agile at Scale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have all these great teams, but no idea what to task them with.  I’d really like to pay them to work on something more valuable than setting a Guinness World Record for stacking K-Cups or looking for a job elsewhere.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;em&gt;Business Agility&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listed a transition example in there.  Some groups want to scale up right away, primarily because they’ve got all the people and resources lined up to do so.  This is one of the best recipes for failure I’ve seen.  To do something well at scale, large scale that is, means that it can be done well at the &lt;em&gt;smallest level&lt;/em&gt; first.  Start with problems, scale up problems.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/sneeches.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/sneeches.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s part of the problem we see with Agility at Scale opinions right now.  We’ve got the Agile Teams ideas down pat.  Communication patterns, making work visible, cross-functional teams, all that stuff is well known at the team level.  That doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean that everyone is already doing it well.  If they were, we wouldn’t still be teaching Scrum, Kanban, and team dynamics sessions to hundreds of clients a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still a lot of noise with Agile at Scale because lots of people struggle with it.  They start too quick or grow unsustainably on process, not principle, following their success.  There is a huge market for this stuff.  The right way to approach the problem of Agile at Scale is often different depending on a number of factors from the size of the organization, what the product is, how the org interacts with customers, and what history is carried that has to be overcome.  Thankfully, a lot of people are experimenting with Agile at Scale.  We’re learning a lot on the backs of many who are living it day in and day out thanks to the stories they share and the updates that get made to the frameworks they are leveraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to Business Agility, a rather amorphous term that is &lt;em&gt;still being invented&lt;/em&gt; even as we live it.  The ideas have just started coming out in compiled form within the last five (okay, six) years.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://theleanstartup.com/&#34;&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://management30.com/&#34;&gt;Management 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Leaders-Guide-Radical-Management/dp/0470548681&#34;&gt;The Leader’s Guide to Radical Management&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Culture-Eats-Strategy-Lunch-Coffman/dp/0615577962&#34;&gt;Culture Eats Strategy for Lunch&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.workrules.net/&#34;&gt;Work Rules!&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tablegroup.com/oh&#34;&gt;The Advantage&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startwithwhy.com/&#34;&gt;Start With Why&lt;/a&gt;.  All of these books, the leaders behind them, and the movements they have created have a common message running through them.  The SolutionsIQ article I link to teeters on the edge of it, yet the word choice could potentially lead one astray.  The common message is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Organizational health is the biggest factor of success, the only strategic advantage of importance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that for a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something implied here, especially when looking at Agile Teams and Agile at Scale.  &lt;em&gt;Business Agility has nothing to do with products&lt;/em&gt;.  Business Agility has everything to do with a healthy team, bound together around a purpose they agree upon.  Products that people love, people who are aligned with that purpose, fall out of the equation.  And when you look at the speed of change in nearly any market, the immense potential to disrupt well-seated titans of an industry, this is the only thing that makes sense.  Products are temporary, and thus so are the successes from them.  Alignment, health, and adaptability of the company are what will allow the company to pivot towards success rather than fail.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/kids-hands-holding-plants.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/kids-hands-holding-plants.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even if you’ve never heard the term Business Agility before, or have no idea what organizational health looks like, I have a feeling it’s moving around at the back of your subconscious.  It’s standing there, saying, &amp;ldquo;Hey, this is good!  You want to be happy at work.  You want you team to be happy too, and you know you can do great things for your community together.&amp;rdquo;  At the same time, your conscious mind is jumping at what’s pressing &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;.  Perhaps it’s trying to figure out how to get all these agile teams working in harmony on the product.  Perhaps it’s speaking words of caution and fear about what the future might hold for your job or division if the organization were to change its structure to support a more healthy way of operating.  A way of operating based on principles and vision, not products, that will ultimately help the organization succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know how that feels.  It can be better, and there are so many wonderful people out here who want to help.  Take that step towards Business Agility and learn what it feels like to truly experience success at work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>