<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agile on Rich with Agility</title>
    <link>http://richvisotcky.com/tags/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agile on Rich with Agility</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rich Visotcky, All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 23:02:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://richvisotcky.com/tags/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for scaling retrospectives</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/tips-for-scaling-retrospectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 23:02:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/tips-for-scaling-retrospectives/</guid>
      <description>Having a retrospective is an important part of the inspect/adapt loop for any team. No matter the batch size of your work, from one item at a time to a month&amp;rsquo;s worth of work, it can be helpful for people to periodically and regularly look at how they&amp;rsquo;re operating and ask what they could change in their personal or work process to make things a bit better. That self introspection can be daunting for many, even with a team of people who work closely with and trust each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility and the Healthy Organization</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 16:35:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/</guid>
      <description>A coworker recently pointed me to an image from a SolutionsIQ blog post The Third Wave of Agile which I’ve included below. The article calls out three areas in Agile thinking - Agile Teams, Agile at Scale, and Business Agility - with key events that either fostered the growth of opinions or reeled them in towards consensus. It’s a good read, one to add to your list after this post. &amp;lt;wink wink&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming the Karate Kid of Agile</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/becoming-the-karate-kid-of-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/becoming-the-karate-kid-of-agile/</guid>
      <description>The year is 1984. You move to a new city and now some kids are beating you up because you&amp;rsquo;re getting friendly with the ex­-girlfriend of one of them. You need to learn how to defend yourself.
Okay, so you&amp;rsquo;re probably not The Karate Kid. Much has changed in 30 years. Your competition is gaining market share, and you&amp;rsquo;re struggling to keep up. You need to take action in the new year and adopting Agile techniques seems like a way to compete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation Compliance with Scrum</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/regulation-compliance-with-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/regulation-compliance-with-scrum/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s always a joy to see individuals whose work involves lots of regulation come through Scrum training with questions around process, timing, documentation and so on. These questions highlight very well that Scrum is not the waterfall process they&amp;rsquo;re accustomed to. It makes perfect sense; the language for regulation was written when waterfall was the dominant process. The great thing is, Scrum and compliance already work together better than you may think.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>