<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rich with Agility</title>
    <link>http://richvisotcky.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rich with Agility</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rich Visotcky, All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 21:28:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://richvisotcky.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Compensate me appropriately</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/compensate-me-appropriately</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 21:28:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/compensate-me-appropriately</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;GE has been making managerial news lately as they &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-06-06/ge-studies-scrapping-annual-raise-in-nod-to-shifting-priorities&#34;&gt;begin their shift&lt;/a&gt; away from annual raises much like they shifted away from annual performance reviews.  It got me thinking about my compensation preferences, and the many discussions I&amp;rsquo;ve had with coworkers over the years about the same.  In every company I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for I&amp;rsquo;ve had a conversation with my employer about trading pay for extra time off.  This rarely jibed with the vacation policy of my employer and required comprehensive questioning.  If I work overtime, can I bank it as PTO instead of getting paid extra?  Can I get some overtime pay and some PTO?  Can I take leave without pay?  All yes/no questions that are anything but simple to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are motivated by money inasmuch as it acts as a proxy for fulfilling basic needs.  Dan Pink &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/u6XAPnuFjJc?t=285&#34;&gt;pointed this out&lt;/a&gt; in his book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danpink.com/books/drive/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and stated simply that people should be paid enough to take the issue of money off the table.  That&amp;rsquo;s probably a bit more than basic needs for most people in modern society.  They also want compensation that allows them to do the things they find important in life.  That might be to build shelter for low-income families, to sail around the world, or to pick up a new book every week to read over the weekend.  Once needs are met, money doesn&amp;rsquo;t act much as a motivator.  In fact, it can &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2013/04/does-money-really-affect-motiv&#34;&gt;become a demotivator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-annual-raise-dancing-with-two-left-feet:47ed58815314839321a73d286c29add6&#34;&gt;The annual raise - dancing with two left feet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see the demotivating effects of money during annual salary adjustments, a ritual dreaded by both employer and employee.  Annual salary adjustments along with annual performance reviews are, as Erik Weber puts it, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.erikweberconsulting.com/blog/2016/6/14/apr&#34;&gt;antiquated practices&lt;/a&gt; not fit for today&amp;rsquo;s organizations.  If your salary is adjusted annually, think back to the last year.  How happy were you with the adjustment?  What influence did you have over setting your new salary?  How connected did the change feel to the work that you perform?  If these questions left you feeling a little low, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone.  Employers tend to stick to a formula including things like rank, longevity, annual performance, and variance from market pay.  Feels really tied to your accomplishments, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as employees are often left disappointed following an annual salary adjustment, employers bear their fair share of anguish.  If you can&amp;rsquo;t at least provide annually a raise that meets cost of living changes you&amp;rsquo;re going to disappoint your workers.  This is table stakes, folks.  This goes beyond corporate budgeting for raises and doling them out &lt;del&gt;fairly&lt;/del&gt; evenly independent of an employee&amp;rsquo;s contributions.  That is likely to disengage your staff quickly as they all discuss what poor raises they got for the year after receiving &lt;em&gt;glowing&lt;/em&gt; annual performance reviews.  Sounds like the kind of thing any manager would be excited to get to work on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-annual-pay:47ed58815314839321a73d286c29add6&#34;&gt;Beyond annual pay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When rewards are temporally related to the actions taken they are much more impactful.  For pay, this could mean more frequent adjustments of salary.  If an employee develops a new level of competence related to their job which can yield a valuable return for the business, why not reward them immediately with an increase in pay?  Note: these aren&amp;rsquo;t bonuses awarded for singular achievement or company milestones (Erik &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.erikweberconsulting.com/blog/2016/6/14/apr&#34;&gt;has something to say&lt;/a&gt; about bonuses too), these are true salary adjustments reflective of changes with long-term benefits for the organization.  This signals to the employee they are moving in the right direction, that they don&amp;rsquo;t need a new job title to increase their value, and their efforts are worthwhile to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the frequency of rewards is just one part of the equation, pay only goes so far.  What might people really want?  Ask them.  Some want flexibility of time to meet their work and personal goals. Others might want the chance to do something outrageous in pursuit of the group&amp;rsquo;s mission.  Acknowledge and reward them for that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/astro_teller_the_unexpected_benefit_of_celebrating_failure&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;even if they fail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Regardless of what you try, check the pulse of your team and be ready to try something else.  No matter the specific incentives a person may be swayed by, we all want the same thing at the core - &lt;em&gt;to be compensated fairly and appropriately for the value we bring to our organizations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition away from annual salary adjustments as the primary means to compensate people in ways that matter to them and let people know they are valued does not have to be drastic or costly.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://management30.com/product/kudo-cards/&#34;&gt;Kudo cards&lt;/a&gt; can be great starters to increasing feedback cycles which combined with &lt;a href=&#34;https://management30.com/product/workouts/merit-money-bonus-systems/&#34;&gt;merit money&lt;/a&gt; offer simple team-based rewards.  I also suggest experimenting with experiential rewards over financial ones for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/3tPGPh&#34;&gt;memory&lt;/a&gt; that becomes associated with them.  The journey isn&amp;rsquo;t simple, but the rewards of a happy, engaged and retained workforce are worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for scaling retrospectives</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/tips-for-scaling-retrospectives</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 23:02:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/tips-for-scaling-retrospectives</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Having a retrospective is an important part of the inspect/adapt loop for any team.  No matter the batch size of your work, from one item at a time to a month&amp;rsquo;s worth of work, it can be helpful for people to periodically and regularly look at how they&amp;rsquo;re operating and ask what they could change in their personal or work process to make things a bit better.  That self introspection can be daunting for many, even with a team of people who work closely with and trust each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When expanding this to many teams, the challenges expand immensely beyond teasing out the quiet voice.  How does information get processed by the group?  How do they figure out what to take action on?  How are they accountable for their actions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are some thoughts to help your organization the next time you gather as a community for a retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;elect-representatives:bc3029f57c4fbc46d9f27b295ed63e70&#34;&gt;Elect representatives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to keep the group size manageable is to have elected representatives from each team participate.  Each team selects members from their own team, a maximum number pre-determined by the group at large, to represent their insights and ideas to the larger audience.  This empowers teams to select a person or persons they trust to represent their ideas and empowers the individual(s) selected to take action on behalf of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-the-focus-on-the-system:bc3029f57c4fbc46d9f27b295ed63e70&#34;&gt;Keep the focus on the system&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When having a scaled retrospective, it&amp;rsquo;s important that participants keep their discussion focused on the system as a whole.  The natural tendency for people is to bring up issues that are affecting their team.  There&amp;rsquo;s a time and place for this, and it&amp;rsquo;s in the team&amp;rsquo;s own retrospective.  Teams need time to sort out problems unique to their own group, problems which may or may not exist across the collection of teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A system focus can surface issues that one team alone may not be able to see or make much headway on.  Likewise, focusing on things which only affect the entire collective can help to remove a &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s not my problem&amp;rdquo; attitude from attendees.  Everyone in attendance should be a part of that system, so in some way the items being discussed affect them.  By seeking to work on and improve things which affect the whole, we can improve our global capability to work towards our shared mission and goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gathering-data:bc3029f57c4fbc46d9f27b295ed63e70&#34;&gt;Gathering data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the group to figure out what they should improve, they first need to gather information.  Just like regular retrospectives, starting out with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.retrospectives.com/pages/retroPrimeDirective.html&#34;&gt;Retrospective Prime Directive&lt;/a&gt; can be a great way to bring everyone together to share information transparently and not turn teams against each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A difficulty with bringing together a large number of people, some of whom may not work together all that frequently, is getting them to talk.  Think about the times you&amp;rsquo;re at a presentation and the speaker asks for audience input.  How long does it usually take for the first person to share their voice?  Usually the main detractors from speaking in that scenario are fears of public humiliation and general follow the crowd mentality.  In the workplace, this effect can be amplified.  However, if we hope to learn anything about the previous iteration and make a plan to improve in the next, we need input from the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One simple technique to get information flowing is to split the group.  This seems counter-intuitive since we just brought all these disparate teams together!  The smaller groups will help create the intimacy people need to feel comfortable sharing and be heard.  Split once into groups of 3-5 people using a simple exercise.  Try not to split on team lines for a more diverse set of viewpoints.  Task these groups to come up with topics to discuss.  Bring the information back to the group as a whole, then reform into new teams based on affinity to topics that people want to discuss.  Have them retrospect on their topic in a timeboxed session then bring findings and action plans back to everyone.  While you may end up with large groups in the second round, you will certainly know which topics seem most important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another suggestion that co-trainer &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scrum.org/about-the-blog/dan-sloan/&#34;&gt;Dan Sloan&lt;/a&gt; offered up was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liberatingstructures.com/1-1-2-4-all/&#34;&gt;1-2-4 All&lt;/a&gt; technique.  This activity starts off with people individually coming up with their own ideas and writing them down.  They then pair up and build on those ideas.  They pair again, now in foursomes, and develop the pair ideas further.  Finally, each foursome shares back with the group one important item from their discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-to-action:bc3029f57c4fbc46d9f27b295ed63e70&#34;&gt;Getting to action&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another place in which the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.retrospectives.com/pages/retroPrimeDirective.html&#34;&gt;Retrospective Prime Directive&lt;/a&gt; comes in handy.  We must believe that the people who participated in the retrospective did the best job they could and we should honor them for that.  Decisions they made are the best they could come up with at the time, and it would at least be worth trying their actions.  We can always make another change at a later time once we&amp;rsquo;ve learned more from their plan of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, when it comes down to &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; takes on the action item(s), this does not necessarily have to be the responsibility of every member of every team.  Some action items may only require the dedicated efforts of a few individuals to make some progress and help the group out as a whole.  Teams need to give those who shoulder this responsibility the time and support needed to accomplish these goals.  It may cause strain on their specific team, yet if their efforts can provide more value to all than the cost of that struggle if will be worth it for the greater good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;thanks-to-the-community:bc3029f57c4fbc46d9f27b295ed63e70&#34;&gt;Thanks to the community&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a topic that came up among a few of my fellow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrum.org/Find-a-Scrum-Trainer&#34;&gt;Scrum.org PSTs&lt;/a&gt; during a face-to-face gathering.  Our community meets several times a year in this way to deepen relationships, share knowledge, and tackle problems facing our group.  It&amp;rsquo;s wonderful to share experiences with each other, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I can share them with you here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility and the Healthy Organization</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/agility-and-the-healthy-organization</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 16:35:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/agility-and-the-healthy-organization</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A coworker recently pointed me to an image from a SolutionsIQ blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.solutionsiq.com/the-third-wave-of-agile/&#34;&gt;The Third Wave of Agile&lt;/a&gt; which I’ve included below.  The article calls out three areas in Agile thinking - Agile Teams, Agile at Scale, and Business Agility - with key events that either fostered the growth of opinions or reeled them in towards consensus.  It’s a good read, one to add to your list &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; this post. &amp;lt;wink wink&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/waves-of-agility.png&#34; alt=&#34;© 2016 SolutionsIQ. All rights reserved.&#34; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I got something out of this graph that goes a bit beyond the original article - ideas around what people are asking for versus what they feel or fear they need even if they aren’t ready to admit it yet.  I believe Agile Teams and Agile at Scale focus on products; Business Agility treats products as a liability and organizational health as an asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each wave is basically a problem statement.  It’s saying &amp;ldquo;How do I/We do &amp;lt;insert wave&amp;gt; well?&amp;rdquo;  The higher the crest, the more pundits you see crawling out from cracks in the walls, descending from the skies, arriving by the boatload to state their opinion.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/vikings.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problems people are really bringing forward are rarely phrased that way.  Instead I more often hear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want to build this awesome product.  How can I get my team to do it without taking 18 months?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;em&gt;Agile Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want to build this awesome product and have money to throw out the window, so I hired 70 people out of the gate so I can get this done in 4 months.  How can I get them to build the product without taking 3 years?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;em&gt;Agile Teams, Agile at Scale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have all these great teams, and my product is a mess.  How do I get it back on track?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;em&gt;Agile at Scale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have all these great teams, but no idea what to task them with.  I’d really like to pay them to work on something more valuable than setting a Guinness World Record for stacking K-Cups or looking for a job elsewhere.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;em&gt;Business Agility&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listed a transition example in there.  Some groups want to scale up right away, primarily because they’ve got all the people and resources lined up to do so.  This is one of the best recipes for failure I’ve seen.  To do something well at scale, large scale that is, means that it can be done well at the &lt;em&gt;smallest level&lt;/em&gt; first.  Start with problems, scale up problems.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/sneeches.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve got the Agile Teams ideas down pat.  Communication patterns, making work visible, cross-functional teams - all that stuff is well known at the team level.  That doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean that everyone is already doing it well.  If they were, we wouldn’t still be teaching Scrum, Kanban, and team dynamics sessions to hundreds of clients a year.  With the team working well together, they can get back to focusing on the product.  That’s part of the problem we see with Agility at Scale right now; it’s assumed at the smallest level things are working just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still a lot of noise with Agile at Scale because lots of people struggle with it.  They start too quick or grow unsustainably on process, not principle, following their success.  The right way to approach the problem of Agile at Scale often differs depending on a number of factors - size/structure of the organization, what the product is, interactions with customers, etc.  This added complexity drags product development down with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, a lot of people are experimenting with Agile at Scale.  We’re learning a lot on the backs of many who are living it day in and day out.  Thanks to the stories they share the prevailing ideas are updated and we get a little closer to consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to Business Agility, a rather amorphous term that is &lt;em&gt;still being invented&lt;/em&gt; even as we live it.  The ideas have just started coming out in compiled form within the last five (okay, six) years.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://theleanstartup.com/&#34;&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://management30.com/&#34;&gt;Management 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Leaders-Guide-Radical-Management/dp/0470548681&#34;&gt;The Leader’s Guide to Radical Management&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Culture-Eats-Strategy-Lunch-Coffman/dp/0615577962&#34;&gt;Culture Eats Strategy for Lunch&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.workrules.net/&#34;&gt;Work Rules!&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tablegroup.com/oh&#34;&gt;The Advantage&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startwithwhy.com/&#34;&gt;Start With Why&lt;/a&gt;.  I believe all of these books and the movements they created have a common message running through them.  The SolutionsIQ article I link to teeters on the edge of it, yet the word choice could potentially lead one astray.  That common message is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Organizational health is the biggest factor of success, the only strategic advantage of importance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that for a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something implied here, especially when looking at Agile Teams and Agile at Scale.  &lt;em&gt;Business Agility has nothing to do with products&lt;/em&gt;.  Business Agility has everything to do with a healthy team, bound together around a purpose they agree upon.  Products that people love, people who are aligned with that purpose, fall out of the equation.  When you look at the speed of change in nearly any market, the immense potential to disrupt well-seated titans of an industry, this is the only thing that makes sense.  Products are temporary, and thus so are the successes from them.  Alignment, health, and adaptability of the company are what will allow the company to pivot towards success rather than fail.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/agility-and-the-healthy-organization/kids-hands-holding-plants.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even if you’ve never heard the term Business Agility before, or have no idea what organizational health looks like, I have a feeling it’s moving around at the back of your subconscious.  It’s standing there, saying, &amp;ldquo;Hey, this is good!  You want to be happy at work.  You want you team to be happy too, and you know you can do great things for your community together.&amp;rdquo;  At the same time, your conscious mind is jumping at what’s pressing &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;.  Perhaps it’s trying to figure out how to get all these agile teams working in harmony on the product.  Perhaps it’s speaking words of caution and fear about what the future might hold for your job or division if the organization were to change its structure to support a more healthy way of operating.  A way of operating based on principles and vision, not products, that will ultimately help the organization succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know how that feels.  It can be better, and there are so many wonderful people out here who want to help.  Take that step towards Business Agility and learn what it feels like to truly experience success at work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming the Karate Kid of Agile</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/becoming-the-karate-kid-of-agile</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/becoming-the-karate-kid-of-agile</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The year is 1984. You move to a new city and now some kids are beating you up because you&amp;rsquo;re getting friendly with the ex­-girlfriend of one of them. You need to learn how to defend yourself.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/becoming-the-karate-kid-of-agile/man-who-catch-fly.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Okay, so you&amp;rsquo;re probably not The Karate Kid. Much has changed in 30 years. Your competition is gaining market share, and you&amp;rsquo;re struggling to keep up. You need to take action in the new year and adopting Agile techniques seems like a way to compete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps your team creates customized software for clients. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re on a support team that works tickets for seven different systems ranging from true bug fixes to feature enhancements. It could be that your team is trying to revamp corporate policies and tooling to protect customer data. &lt;a href=&#34;http://wikispeed.org/join-the-team/the-wikispeed-process/&#34;&gt;Or you could be building a car.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen lots of groups say they&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo; because they go through the mechanics of some particular method and wonder why they&amp;rsquo;re not immensely successful. I&amp;rsquo;ll often hear: &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re doing Scrum. We have daily stand ups, everyone is co­located, and we show off our software every month.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those same people, after doing a little more digging, say things like &amp;ldquo;Well, we show off our software every month, but we haven&amp;rsquo;t released anything to our users yet. It&amp;rsquo;s only been 10 months though. Good thing we haven&amp;rsquo;t released it too, because there are parts we haven&amp;rsquo;t tested yet and really, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if they&amp;rsquo;d work when we flip the switch on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does not sound like a promising situation for the company or its clients. Any Agile method supports the principles laid out in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemanifesto.org&#34;&gt;Manifesto for Agile Software Development.&lt;/a&gt; Generally they favor a focus on people and their interactions, getting working product at regular (and short) intervals, and fostering a culture that is responsive to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Agile methods, there sure are a lot of them. We have Scrum, eXtreme Programming (XP), Lean, Feature Driven Development (FDD), Dynamic systems development method (DSDM), Kanban, and Scrumban amongst others. Just check &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.versionone.com/pdf/2013-state-of-agile-survey.pdf#page=7&#34;&gt;VersionOne&amp;rsquo;s State of Agile Survey&lt;/a&gt; to see the large number of ideas that our industry is experimenting with, a list that&amp;rsquo;s surely grown since publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your unique situation, simply doing what all the other cool kids are doing may not offer you the best chance at success. With so many options, how does one know which to use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paint-the-whole-fence:67dc0d01281ef76a694365c98822b227&#34;&gt;Paint the Whole Fence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great place to start is taking a look at how complex your effort is.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/becoming-the-karate-kid-of-agile/Ralph_Stacey_Chart.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The above is a model by Ralph Stacey applied to three major factors in product development: requirements, technology, and people. The complexity of a problem is determined by how close or far from agreement and certainty we are about various things and how much people factor in. Likewise, the more complex the problem the more likely a candidate it is to apply &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empirical_process_(process_control_model)&#34;&gt;empirical process control&lt;/a&gt;, preferred by Agile methods, over defined process control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different Agile methods thrive in different complexity domains and there is definitely overlap. For simple to complicated efforts, we might be best served with Kanban and Lean principles to help us visualize our work, measure flow, and look for opportunities to improve what&amp;rsquo;s already in place to maximize that flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the complicated to complex space, we might rely more on the practices provided by XP to help keep quality high and focus on building something that validates choices made around requirements and technology. At the edge of complicated, Scrum starts to be effective and prevails in the complex domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrum expects that the intersection of market conditions, technical ability, and people&amp;rsquo;s perceptions of a product they can interact with will invariably change what is desired to build into the product next. Teams and stakeholders regularly meet for engaged feedback sessions to validate that the right thing is being built and use that information to drive what should be built next to deliver the most value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we start in the complicated space, but move to the complex? What if while we&amp;rsquo;re in the complex space we create a process that&amp;rsquo;s simple? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R37pbIySnjg#t=88&#34;&gt;Daniel­-san was &amp;ldquo;almost done&amp;rdquo; painting Mr. Miyagi&amp;rsquo;s fence when suddenly, BOOM! ALL the fence!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paint-the-fence-sand-the-floor-wax-the-car-paint-the-house:67dc0d01281ef76a694365c98822b227&#34;&gt;Paint the Fence! Sand the Floor! Wax the Car! Paint the House!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://richvisotcky.com/images/post/becoming-the-karate-kid-of-agile/Daniel-Larusso-Ralph-Macchio.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


Learning a new Agile technique can be very similar, requiring practice before effectiveness and mastery. So what does this have to do with selecting an Agile method or technique?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all Daniel­-san knew was &amp;ldquo;paint the house&amp;rdquo; then he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be very effective at karate. It took floor sanding, car waxing, and house painting as well all brought together to become a karate natural. Being Agile works the same way. You can &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; many different techniques and methods, but bringing the practices and principles from many together as the situation requires to use the right thing at the right time will help you to &amp;ldquo;be&amp;rdquo; Agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally written for Centare, and can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centare.com/becoming-the-karate-kid-of-agile/&#34; title=&#34;Becoming the Karate Kid of Agile&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation Compliance with Scrum</title>
      <link>http://richvisotcky.com/regulation-compliance-with-scrum</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richvisotcky.com/regulation-compliance-with-scrum</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always a joy to see individuals whose work involves lots of regulation come through Scrum training with questions around process, timing, documentation and so on.  These questions highlight very well that Scrum is not the waterfall process they&amp;rsquo;re accustomed to.  It makes perfect sense; the language for regulation was written when waterfall was the dominant process.  The great thing is, Scrum and compliance already work together better than you may think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-empiricism-to-our-advantage:b0107fdd8565f088ebf62f0a95c397a0&#34;&gt;Using empiricism to our advantage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regulation and compliance are complex issues.  There may be contradictory, vague, or incomplete regulations causing confusion as to what needs to be done.  Adding to that, regulations often change over time so understanding the regulation and how to comply with it is continually in flux.  Scrum is a framework designed for doing complex work, so the two naturally fit together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The empirical nature of Scrum gives companies inspection and adaptation points necessary to assess their progress towards compliance with a regulation.  This applies to regulations implemented in software as well as regulations that apply to how software is developed.  The company can frequently inspect the product and its process to assess compliance.  Testing suites, especially automated ones, help to ensure the software never falls out of compliance with the regulation.  Test driven development can also help ensure compliance from the beginning with built in verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-auditing:b0107fdd8565f088ebf62f0a95c397a0&#34;&gt;What about auditing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern ALM tools offer extensive history functions for both source code and work requests which can be queried for auditing purposes.  For example, the exact point in time which the software met a specific regulation as proven through a testing suite can be identified.  Work items on the backlog can be linked to high level regulations and traced down to their implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of financial auditing, the traceability offered by ALM tools can be immensely helpful when understanding the capitalization and expenditures of a software development project.  Turns out, agile development practices &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/articles/agile-capitalization&#34;&gt;are incredibly helpful&lt;/a&gt; with financial regulations.  From a capitalization and expenditure standpoint, Scrum can help companies reduce tax liability and free up money for the staff they need to realize their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB) guidelines may have been written with waterfall processes in mind, but they give us some guidance that quickly apply to agile software development.  In general, any &amp;ldquo;Preliminary Project Phase&amp;rdquo; work, that is, anything before you begin sprinting and actually doing work, is an operational expense.  Work done while sprinting can be capitalized, and maintenance work is expensed.  Since teams may very well work on bugs for a released product in the same sprint that they are creating or enhancing features, some of the cost may need to be expensed.  In this case, the relative point estimates teams assigned to the work can be used to determine the proportion which can be capitalized and which can be expensed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While software may be released each sprint, it likely isn&amp;rsquo;t being depreciated each sprint.  A quarterly roll up may suffice.  Work with your financial department to come up with a clear set of rules your company will follow for its reporting practices.  From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/articles/agile-capitalization&#34;&gt;Dan Greening&amp;rsquo;s article&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Auditors recognize that FASB and IASB guidance cannot be routinely applied to new situations. What tax authorities and auditors look for is conformance to law and its spirit, consistent application, and full transparency. We can give them all that, but because agile practice is new, we must understand the law and its motivations, document our capitalization policies and practices, track project work consistently, and be perfectly transparent. This aligns well with agile principles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pat Reed summed this up nicely along with Laszlo Szalvay in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/laszlos/2013-scrum-grcfinal728&#34;&gt;a session&lt;/a&gt; at Agile 2013 encouraging that we &amp;ldquo;Re-evaluate the problem that was trying to be solved when the rules were first written.&amp;rdquo;  The rules don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep your company in the waterfall ages forever.  Use the transparency called for by Scrum to your advantage and develop a set of guidelines that will help, not hinder, your company&amp;rsquo;s ability to deliver value while meeting regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally written for Centare, and can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centare.com/scrum-and-regulation-compliance/&#34; title=&#34;The State of Agility – Regulation Compliance with Scrum&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>